A legend will face his destiny.
Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny is a adventure,
action film directed by James Mangold.
Finding himself in a new era, and approaching retirement, Indy wrestles
with fitting into a world that seems to have outgrown him.
But as the tentacles of an all-too-familiar evil return in the form of an old rival, Indy must don his hat and pick up
his whip once more to make sure an ancient and powerful artifact doesn't fall into the wrong hands.
Indiana Jones, played by Harrison Ford.
Helena, played by Phoebe Waller-Bridge.
Dr. Voller, played by Mads Mikkelsen.
Klaber, played by Boyd Holbrook.
Hauke, played by Olivier Richters.
Teddy, played by Ethann Isidore.
Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny is a 2023 American action-adventure film directed by James
Mangold and written by Mangold, David Koepp, Jez Butterworth and John-Henry Butterworth.
It is the fifth and final in the Indiana Jones film series.
Harrison Ford and John Rhys-Davies reprise their roles from the previous films, with Phoebe Waller-Bridge,
Antonio Banderas, Toby Jones, Boyd Holbrook, Ethann Isidore, and Mads Mikkelsen joining the cast.
Set in 1969, the film follows Jones and his estranged goddaughter, Helena,
who are trying to locate a powerful artifact before Dr.
Jürgen Voller, a Nazi-turned-NASA scientist, who plans to
use it to alter the outcome of World War II.
Plans for a fifth Indiana Jones film date back to 1979, when a deal was made
with Paramount Pictures to produce five Indiana Jones films.
Lucas began researching potential plot devices for a fifth film in
2008, and Koepp was hired to write the screenplay in 2016.
In 2018, Jonathan Kasdan replaced Koepp but later left the project.
Originally set for release in 2019, the film faced delays
due to rewrites and the COVID-19 pandemic.
Steven Spielberg was initially set to direct but stepped
down in 2020, with Mangold taking over.
Filming began in June 2021 in various locations including the United
Kingdom, Italy, and Morocco, wrapping in February 2022.
Franchise composer John Williams returned to score the film, earning nominations for Best Original
Score at the 96th Academy Awards and Best Score at the 66th Annual Grammy Awards.
Williams won the Grammy Award for Best Instrumental
Composition for "Helena's Theme".
Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny premiered out of competition at the 76th Cannes Film Festival on May 18,
2023, and was released in the United States on June 30, by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It grossed $384 million, becoming a box-office bomb due to
being one of the most expensive films ever made.
The film explores themes of melancholy, treasure
hunt, ancient rome, sequel, flashback.